Happiest. Movie. Ever.
Trolls World Tour is a family, animation, comedy film directed by Walt Dohrn.
Queen Poppy and Branch make a surprising discovery — there are other Troll worlds beyond their
own, and their distinct differences create big clashes between these various tribes.
When a mysterious threat puts all of the Trolls across the land in danger, Poppy, Branch, and their band of friends must
embark on an epic quest to create harmony among the feuding Trolls to unite them against certain doom.
Poppy (voice), played by Anna Kendrick.
Branch (voice), played by Justin Timberlake.
Cooper (voice), played by Ron Funches.
Barb (voice), played by Rachel Bloom.
Biggie (voice), played by James Corden.
Delta Dawn (voice), played by Kelly Clarkson.
Trolls World Tour is a 2020 American animated jukebox musical comedy film by DreamWorks
Animation, based on the Good Luck Trolls dolls created by Thomas Dam.
The sequel to Trolls (2016) and the second installment in the franchise, the
film was directed by Walt Dohrn and co-directed by David P.
Smith, from a screenplay by Maya Forbes, Wallace Wolodarsky, Elizabeth Tippet, and the
writing team of Jonathan Aibel and Glenn Berger, and a story by Aibel and Berger.
The film features the voices of Anna Kendrick, Justin Timberlake, Rachel Bloom, James Corden, Ron
Funches, Kelly Clarkson, Anderson .Paak, Sam Rockwell, George Clinton, and Mary J.
The film follows Poppy and Branch as they discover more troll tribes
that represent music genres other than their own.
Troubles arise when Queen Barb of the Rock tribe plans to overthrow the foreign music genres to unite
the trolls under rock music, prompting Poppy and Branch to unite the tribes and stop her.
After the first film's release, a sequel was announced in February 2017,
with Kendrick and Timberlake returning to their roles.
Much of the new cast was signed from May 2018 to June 2019.
The custom marking animation to promote the film was
provided by Minimo VFX and Jellyfish Pictures.
Trolls World Tour was released by Universal Pictures in the United States in a limited number of theaters on
April 10, 2020, due to the COVID-19 pandemic and was simultaneously released on video on demand.
AMC Theatres subsequently announced they would no longer distribute the studio's films,
though this was later reversed after AMC and Universal agreed on a new contract.
The film has grossed $48 million.
A sequel, Trolls Band Together, was released in 2023.
The film explores themes of dancing, friendship, concert, country music, guitar.
The tone is lighthearted.